so don't worry about setting up
yorkie max files in one myself
will go through
how to do nothing
grab the latest version
your thoughts and bookmarks and things
time it'll be easier
and back up a little bit
this figure is in the uh... the category
of i was hoping to show it sometime
during the semester
but i want to give you a sense of how i
view g_i_s_ because this is different
for
many different people
what you're trying to accomplish is
not always the same
and how people view
what it is to be uh... energy i have
personally what they're not that's up
technicians pot or highlevel research
spot i kinda feel like they could be and
all of the above
so we show you this is for of how i
think i've g_i_s_ it took me
giving lectures in research tools in
past years to try and
decide that i didn't like the
definitions that i saw for people
because they have really don't
don't feel like they include
what we do u has
uh... three mac version waterways
pudgy i_n_s_'s focused towards the city
their world in our world phone always
lineup very well although i think our
worldly compasses with day to you
their roles have a subset
of what goes on
so the sort of walking through
this really were off as not perfect it
just sort of a conceptual thing was
going on
but i see
what we do it yes annmarie mapping is
your something the world's fair
collecting
uh... location time
alert for today down here certainty and
meditate about
the world as you go around
in the shipper wherever you are
cashing stock
and there's
blankets and you can hear
itinerary for this is your level zero
data it's your raw unprocessed
the record of public us and i'm kind of
mentality going on here but we're
working with data
and that's going off to other people and
maybe get some stuff back from them
it goes possibly cures and conversion
and your data store
and from there
utenti view data transformations you
play out rooms to it
a_d_ reproduction the opposite of the
things you can do your kid to manipulate
it
you do visualization failure to demat
styler three new york
how everyone visualize you could turn
into audio i could see that
visualization if you wanna listen to
your multi gate or something
apply queries but they are not asking
you questions
and you might even be physical output so
sometime toward the rippled makeup
physical model of the sea for a lack of
physical printer
to make a plastic model of my god
and all that's leading to
informed decisionmaking so basically
you're trying to to make decisions with
the if you were going to use it or
something
defect the world
why did you spend time collecting it
so this could be in climate change
decisions that could be
navigating a ship part char
you know that going to hear that you
keep producing a chart that comes out
you go to somebody
it could be coastal marine spatial
planning if you are government person
eager to be any number of things
if it's worth a person doing g_i_s_ for
city this could be you're right though
jordan sister house in the listed apply
to where you live
you're making decisions based on
dot for your life which are also feeling
that back into the air approx around
back to you
were reporting more data
so you make some decisions we don't know
enough about the u_s_ waters
to being told a couple of what we know
was out there
if we were all good would stop sending
out no shifted survey yukio cape last
year was the last year notre dame we're
done
out salters young take a vacation
that's not what happens you briefly co
take the output of this
feedback to beginning in state where do
we need a survey next year
we gotta keep going back and quite a few
more data
will dusted for decision making
there were a bsn shifts next year
because we have limited resources first
love to have way more survey shirts and
hats
so it's this kind of group of going
through this process that is what we're
trying to talk about in this class
academic a lot of different tools
for the low-level simply writing scripts
to read to be using high-level things
like carrots anarchy ayaz
and be able to mix and match all those
things
you end up with this model of the
world's this is for alive you
yes it's a high-level dispersing some of
my biases in there and
encourage you to find
task of the people and find out what
other people are saying about what they
think this process is because not
everybody can sit at the same thing
i'd make sure that i've got
error and uncertainty and i've been in
there in a lot of people don't want to
deal with that kind of stuff
how ordinary more emphasis of it and
that there might be huge things and
everything else around that might be
small
de point asp people as you go through
your quiz and as you leave here
what how they view data and elected as
the influence
that the whole process of our lives
warranty this morning if we're gonna dig
into
he's a guy i find to you first
update using
material our clocks
service not available for download is
eighteen oh yes
we're gonna play with i a python
bookmarks
but that we're gonna go in and work
better at that
part of a little bit more
and i think you three we have two more
aspect file so we can try and work on
command-line arguments will reprocess
mobile filed the same time to look at a
couple different ways to do that
and forget time read or write a came out
and for a train wreck and ask you well
database
we're not going to get too far and ask
you all that you always have seen
writing and ask you all database
and bold
try and show
lameta printout graphical tools you can
actually take a look at your data that
you've written at moorpark spreadsheet
style from the database so let me jump
in to youtube
the notes here
we're going to start by updating before
we go on with our partners
so start up by python
summer show you guys are unique features
and i python i'm still going to know
some of them have been asking a lot of
questions of the ipod funky
if they're listen to this at berkeley i
have preaching fear l
so will go ahead and say
bookmark
dash health now bookmark is a part of my
python it's not a normal part on command
i had to bookmark your should not have
anything in there yet
your jewelry point right now
so what cd into till dislodged
projects
research tools
press answer
we do an ls you'll see that we've got
are checked out copy of the classes
begin
uh... collectively or so
if you want to say this location
amici easier to get back to you
for example you know i always remember
everywhere and ask if you get more more
going on and it's hard to remember
everything we can save bookmark
h_d_ class so for me that needs to carry
all box location
you because bookmark whatever you wanted
that made sense to you
coopers and figuring out clever bookmark
spec
yugoslav better
tv presenter and now if you do a
bookmark
dash l
you guys should have
you won't have a c twenty four years
we'll have the htc g class
link no point act-up respond this
that is going on one bookmark we used to
but more to the government sees see how
they work in a bit
would seem to bookmark
now on the net
dylan update
on
the material files that we have here but
look what we do that i'm in a single
i'll look at what's in that directory
so if we do an ls
solis flash
before dot taxed cecil reason that
greater then decided to file
so we're saving what our director looks
like the forward on the update
and hopefully you guys have not updated
yet today
all you had to officials
uh... yes
okay will do an ls that sell and pardon
me for a second here
walters go
and be who make a raymond change
what will say is how bout
please do not
update
org t
esther
wesley
uh... dear not swine i encyclical
sold citizens up a little bit is that he
gave no thanksgiving week civil staged g
status if you can watch me do you think
your your stuff tonight check things out
so i've got a modified file in here
so i can do it used to be dept
and also the changes about a couple
lines also h_g_ commit
these students
and research
tools are two quick
and then insti push this in the senate
up to the server
make you guys have to update
there is a new team and the severed
don't update yet
so will change it up
for our before
will do it that's helped so would you
along listing and you'll see the profile
who actually changed its easy if you
don't already have a twenty-four
lecturing there
directory
said you know it's not so
grier then
fill the slot before dot taxed
the preview alaska was flashed before
dot text
how location cv into class have been
better
this could be a wonderful lecture today
as i uh...
it was going on rerun i commend them
inside of the class directory
and if we do that
left before we should see all the files
in the class
so we'll see that there is a twenty four
in there
for me if you don't have the guts
so make sure
urine
home research tools projects research
tools class
and they've done that before
and so now we can do
our banks are on the back shell commands
h_g_
removed over of stuff off of that that's
what it's like
you can see it's talking a bit bucket
being here's our updates
through that period change sets with
three changes to one file
we can say at least c update
but with an escalation point for us
ammo then pull those changes in georgia
rectory
and that's bad for me egg i shouldn't
have that then
you don't have to be there now
that we don't do it and a m trying to
get myself resorted here
you know because you have out myself and
her into the world things i haven't
tried before
by a research tools is the best part
about losing control
i guess to leave my tirelessly
and i'm gonna start over
totally okay
so i can go up here and it's it's nice
to managed to clone prime minister right
from the beginning
tonight in case that and
so this that i think that retain control
of your world gets completely messed up
and you can always go back to some other
state without too much trouble
specify papon
cv
research tools yesterday okay so now i
am now where you guys should be
and you've done the before
sanofi do
a c
cid image the poll
update
nothing's changed for me to register to
check out
but now we've been hearing say
el estado
greater than the senate to file so will
slash after
tfc
so you can see on my desktop here at
these two files before and after
we're gonna run addict commands to check
out what was the difference between
those two files
diff is a great programmers tool for
seeing what goes on
thrift aidid
and here for a minute
xr hurt
go find those are my notes
so there was no g_s_ lecturer and set up
and were right here at this different
say deaf
dash dash
at it
abandon the front push up command
unified
there's lots of different way to present
their signifies kind of a friendlier way
till slash before dot t_ xti
until slash after dot t_ s_ t_
you were a couple will look fairly
simple mine is going to look a little
crazier that
marin is terrible
so my hope was that you would see just a
small one
so if you're lucky you have is a couple
lines for the plus a minus and with the
directory listing it's kind of annoying
directory listings like to start with
the dash
any wine is hard for the plots
hopefully you have a nicer example which
is a small change
on one file
dorsey airports like new lines and a
minus by old ones
and mine is not within a very good job
being a good example
delivery do that in the video reportage
do you guys can see the fact that you
can do you get to check out what's
change between versions i see a couple
of you've got some nice ones
mobile forces annoyances
so if you seek to minuses
the problem with the ls dot shell as it
starts off physically with
minus r_w_ for
this is not
this would be eighty if this is a
directory
so if you're seeing a minus out here or
plots out here in the first column
this is what it on a life being adamant
these minuses are just
a part of the texas after so it's
confusing
it takes a long time to get used to
looking at this
they're really really helpful
but they're kinda strange
and then up above you'll see plus plus
plus
and minus five points
this issue and you the source file on
the after farley getting itchy and files
comparing
and so showing inflation of the time
which one is that it's a serb withdrew
minus minus minus violinist go into a
possible was fun
that's a really bad example of using
kits upon screen bessie couple you've
got really nice ones on the screens all
redoing an operatic figure and i
the class notes that shows that working
swimmers time-dependent things very
careful what you do
without their notes
so we can now go creator class directory
so we'll see you
ther
fill the slot
class twenty four
seeds will slice class twenty four
and all the things you know the carrot a
second bookmark
since her and working with us today with
a bookmark
c twenty four
too strong for class twenty four
than outside bookmark
dash l
and you'll see that you have a
bookmarked for c twenty four that puts
you at that clock location
an h_g_ class which is where
laboratory fought their pic
is this here's a link to somewhere were
mercurial surface you can create
bookmarks four
if you've got a bunch of different data
sets here working with
and some source code
it might appear barry decreasing
bookmarked for those are to come back
and forth in working for the project a
lot
pretty handy tool to be able to us he
was going on
so we can say
p dvd right now we're in the past twenty
four
and save cv
h_d_ class
and takes you to battling conservative
community
went out somewhere else
before
themselves with garcetti twenty-four so
can't seem to cd twenty four
and we're now back in the class
directory
existed
there's times when it's going to get
confused if you're in a separate er with
their daily is the same name i'm not
sure what's gonna happen
tried that yet to see
markets completely confused or bookmark
this is probably not the best place a
point of view point uh...
thank you cv hasty class probably better
to mix cd of the class
and say bookmark
insti class
before that show
the government notes
so there's a little more sense
summer say cdc twenty four
and get back over to that
closely for gonna work today
these tools that you're gonna
this i would write you didn't want to
use
and if you like them
then given the go
let's go ahead and start about logfile
make sure your in-class twenty-four
anti-clotting start
dash so dash or
log dash class
for me for a private
we do tell us you'll now see that we've
got our
logfile going in there
it will actually go back and before the
stuff we have from before so could you
last
walk las
wifey secret back in
captures all of my messing around
so if you could best thing about this is
if you get part way through you for your
log file glad story and it will go back
and grabbed her history
no similar fun command so we can do
you have a directory history suit detest
so it's going to list all the
directories
that you've been too and you can say
cd
minus
minus one
and you also have
tickets underscore d_h_
is your address richard stephens eighty
h
answered if you could begin shooting
using these directories trees and
suggestions playing around for me to get
comfortable
i'm not there yet in terms of being
really comfortable with them
but more importantly let's create an
alias that you might use fairly often to
do that update actually just didn
so if you get back to the next class
when you want to get ahead of me you
could do it even faster
cific ideally s
this list theories is that are currently
available
and enforcing them
didn't delete my aliases so ive
you'll see the one that about the trade
with you guys
we can say alias
party update for research tools update
and what we did in this updated as we
see the into the directory where the
material stuff lived
ran a steep pull animal rain h_g_ update
and we can do all that and one line
and we don't have to remember that wine
every time
so we can say is
cv till the slash
projects research tools
some info on east c
wholesome make foreign
piece the update
replacing old playing wonderful times
so we have our areas
magic man try pipeline
that we've got archie update which is
the name of our alias or creating
and everything from here on out that
committed a mistake in the alias
in cash
place heart disease here
will protect you from
that cd
so inside that scope there change
directory when you come back out needed
drop back leader hope that's how it
works
so we jump in a directory
semicolon starts a new show command
finish deportees yesterday
fiefdom actually work
yeah i'm really very much of his work
still to strive
epithets
and it's left me in
classpath wannabe
cuz i put myself into the c_d_c_ twenty
background was
so please let haley s
and give us all up
if you want to say that
for future sessions
there's a way to store that
anti-communist or
party update
and that will save it
in your innocence that are permanent
between sessions
so if you have commands you want to run
fairly often the kind of yourself going
on in a certain tasks
unique read a bunch of aliases for those
things saved them in there
when we come back type icon next time
you'll still be there
apple will note down here some these
commands are broken and i fight on zero
point one one
which is the next person f_-one were
using
but i think they said they're going to
come back and
diversified come outside
so never fear they will get fixed
that's dave we're gonna grab it
three different aspect files with
working with just one up for now
so if you copy these three curl commands
copied
and just
widely spaced amid over here in new york
pipeline shell
city often fetch
tumour aspects
to do and how it's done shell once
you've got it
so you should have three-b_ zipped
aspects
and then i've got
three nestle
be unzip command c dot the type of don't
want to
paste
we do know relative s_l_ you'll see that
we've got
three aspect file for us to work with
the bank
and if you
are good in motivating want rice in mt
five sums
to make sure that you've got the same
stuff but i've got
those of the mt five phones
now if you want right after class
you can also create a bash alias
forgot instructions on how to do that
from bash if you'd like to do that
as a file called telus flash
fashion illnesses
you can add into that
so bascially says this is filing your
home directory
and you can put in an alias performance
slightly different between i fight on
the back
three close yourself
yet haven't eagles line here
and put it in quotes
steven craig may has that work further
in bash or and i i thought
alot you guys are export i think it
motivated we won't spend more time on it
and let's go ahead and copy
the source code
i've got to where we lost time section
and we're gonna copy all of that python
code from last time
and placed into an aspect op i file
in your class twenty-four directory
control space on the beginning of uh...
source code
scroll down
getting even longer
becoming a very inefficient way to get
going
all the way down to the bottom where
you've got your and source
matter w copies
india control x control f and watch up
where you are
i bought the or filed in a different
place than haven't copied it to my class
directory this time
so we need to go back to you
till the slash
and if you just typed il slash anywhere
in the find bioline
it'll start over from the top
so class
twenty four
aspect upright
so we're gonna open up a new file should
be blank
who hadn't hit enter
misty and he has been filed press
control why did they saw that in
so it should be any file should be in
your class twenty-four directory
and stated
and amanda quick skim actor worry last
time to remind you all of what we were
working on
since some of the stuff was the first
time you've seen it
we just written
barlow that's that file
that that uh... generator things kinda
strange
creature that will keep returned to us
the difference
for everything that goes with the
special yields
statement down here that returns
datagram sent to slip
my finishes at the funds for abortion
goes off the bottom
that generator finishes up and turns
back to the form of has done
and rate here
we hadn't quite done the specter in four
ec eight c
four datagram index
this is the old style
uh... four datagram
indexing range so just walked over to
the repeated arms that are in the file
and we were asking for
uh... datagram to decode each one
was switched back to it
to use our generator and then we'll go
out to more functional in scotland
so that we can do things like break a
male use tremon arguments and uh...
generally
departments here
so if we're going to use that generator
if you go into your four loop
and still leads
all of that coz
so sorry from datagram index
poetry or decoding datagram
with cv curve place that with our
generator that's gonna return datagram
control w to delete that
so say four datagram
underscore index
promulgated graham
and if we start up with our generator
we saved
load
s fed
file
and sample
thought aspect
this will move through there
but we we don't
now have a number of datagram as an
index would like to be able to
keep track of as we move through this
file which
datagram on
which are busy road and that one two
three seven
flew like the file
the fact that it has a special function
called enumerate
that keeps track of
how many items that come through
so it it take to david graham and to add
to account that goes with it
an abrupt halt parts
datagram index in the datagram
so hopeless will make things all of its
own board down the road as we buildup
khoda mikham with pure datagram much
less coz
so i must say that
and we're gonna give it a shot and see
if i'd meaning typos
sourcesafe
ron aspect upline
you should see
a printout of all the data grams coming
through with their indexes
so we've done a little bit differently
today
if you're seeing run expect up by saying
error file not found the first thing you
should do is do appear to be
right working directory
and
if you're in class time still then you
need to see the
space class twenty c twenty four to do
bookmark dash l
poster the parks
and you have received reports idiocy
faith seafood for
and if you're in class report is not
working do in a last
products are now using a getting an
error in your code
so what happened isn't even a last year
to see we don't have her simple but i
spent
so you had
need to go back in ron the curl command
saddam of data
and that he and his ass
who knows so that's one thing to be
careful what would your or working
across a lot of different directories
so you have to be aware of where you're
at
and what director your you're running
commands from because it has a lot of
implications where you are candidacy
point what happens with some enumerate
here
didn't have anne-marie
and we just had low test that bosnia
returned to us each time through the
datagram
if you're at something enumerate every
time a comeback this will count how many
things that come through
animal add-on
another very boats and number two
they're worth it
uh...
e
we could yes but but here in this case
you're giving a personal choice
so that the program for kids colin well
that's that pile doesn't know so they
want to track the number of the datagram
maybe they do you mean they don't
and if you do this where you build into
your generator
van they have no choice but to deal with
that
to maybe don't need it we don't care
what with a degree in your own dismantle
the law and not care about the number
bandits on a big deal it is wrong with
that
so it sometimes accused of stopping
about the choice of
do here dot we want to have to have that
index always with a when it when you
have a new murray is always going to
have on the front
a number to go with died on the whatever
it took her from that
the next thing read to you is we have
multilateral ets
so we'd like to be able to process them
through
and to be able to handle all of the
estates in the directory
and as a couple ways to do that we're
going to start off with simple
and not so
so clever way of doing it
and then won't step up to the fancier
way and then
the way that i would traditionally do it
was with the command-line argument
parser
that what he was pressed fighting
clearly
the first one
has a very
odd name called glob
t l o v
so it's important blah blah jewel
so what globs job is to do is to take
things like the stars that we used to
dallas and expand them
so the court command will
do things like
deal with the bridges of numbers the
question mark for any character
source a
globe
dot glob
so there's a club module which contains
the club function
it's a start up high
and this will give us all the python
files in the current directory of the
list
so in our case we've got our log we've
got
and they better aspect up either or
working on
or who are now
what are all the dot aspect files in
there
glob dot gov
and have to start a aspect and will see
the three different aspects that we had
now this is
this head of a lot of different stop
with these you can mix it up to you know
as we can say
clogged
quality
two thousand and start
so this gives everything starting with
two thousand ten
and we'll just have one file comeback so
it's a list of just like one
so you can mix this up and and call out
files you want
the trouble is is that if you write a
program like this and you had to someone
else you've now hard coded day if you
could use a all asked if we had
yes but one like this
you're saying how many
process every aspect in this directory
you don't get choice
so where do you want it from mexico
find every aspect that directory the
first time around it's up to do anything
more or anything less
not very flexible
but it does get the job done quickly so
sometimes it is writing a short but a
felon
this is the perfect thing to do and if
you actually look
at the very bottom of the torrent file
after class you're gonna see some code
that i wrote this that's
i don't like it's not written very well
but it got the job done for today
some aspects
there were huge deal
hundreds of megabytes in turn into the
sample files
and i've never been a renews that coz
so i just did a quick
and really horrible during
so was at backlog into are coat
and create
an aspect of private nose had a loop
over a bit different files were to make
a couple changes
tomorrow granted this is great
braiding here
need anymore
this aspect file on the spectator will
reload does
so let's get rid of those two lines
we also are not going tram print out the
number of datagram three now
and give up on that
amorous select this region
number datagram time x_y_z_ hatter thing
and then the four datagram index
datagram enumerate
that was through all the papers and
print them out
if you remember from awhile back
there's a commanding the maximal intense
your coat
it's under
eitan
aidid's shift to regenerate so control
see greater than
go ahead and uh... keyboarding
control c
granted that's four spaces onto
everything
we're now going to have some extra code
word for that
so imports glob
typically you don't want to import
modules
willy nilly throughout the code but for
now we're just gonna put it right next
door or using it
amorous a four
file name
in
dot glob
star dot aspect
so this is going to look through every
aspect in our directory
and narrow
down here with the low test that file we
had
hard coded in a file name
so make sure you delete
everything including the single quotes
serb-controlled w
and replaced that with file name
so our club is going to give us back to
list and we're gonna walk across each of
the file names and
worked through that final
what what a little bit more in seconds
and i had a little bit of tax refund
after that a second
so your code should look
in maine
should look like this
tourism blank lines here
here so we're just
rewritten it
this section here so we've
importer club
we now have a four filing and twelve
o'clock along
microphones say
starter at that
inside of our poorly
we're gonna print out this little hatter
for each one and poor datagram index
remit numerator
over
the dave ramsey in that particular file
so changed file name right there
and then this print is just like before
and this code is going to look a little
where instant mashed living together so
i think it'd get idea to have
to protect the file naming salute to
sourcesafe prints
two-thirds obvious i like to put some
stars or he calls for a minute to sticks
out
around the file name so hopefully
that'll
make a nice little uh... thing we can
see each file starting
who are working on that i'm gonna go
ahead and try that
will save ron
dot pine
and a lot of stuff went by so it's back
up and see what happens
and we're gonna see some quirks in the
affect
that partner so fun there's a lot of
zeros
someone some stuff
and and then try and find beginning
about coming out
which ran off the top
that wasn't fun
forces one for the state of ron aspect
up high
so resume run run automatically handles
that for you
if we were calling the function inside
by itself then we would need to read
said you guys remember that percent
operator with numbers five times wasn't
divide
but it was the remainder
oklahoma below the log
they're really talking about remainders
is that they have as our property
that they make a really good test if you
wanted you every and
thing through the wind
so if we have
a lot of data granted we don't want to
print them on the screen because it was
so much that the scroll background it's
basically lost stuff off the top
you can do something forty percent where
you say every time
we divide by some number in the
remainder of zero
will go ahead and print
so that numbers like every ten
see my ten every time we divide by
tendering your zero
warning or the needful to everytime
high into the loop
and this is something where evening
programmers have been programming for a
long time
haven't seen this kind of trek in what
you see it you might use it allot
i certainly is a lot more at work but
they did if thats
because if it takes it takes an hour
process your data
and you know how many items during the
day that
but if it just if they're running
do-nothing you're gonna get very
frustrated with wondered how far along
and mine
for you to print out everything and skip
you may be overwhelming
so what we can do
is user datagram index
and say if
dated graham
index
montessori and divide by
and most say that the
that every twenty
when that equals zero
we're gonna do our print take cab when i
was on one of the french invented four
spaces
so says
every twenty f
everytime exam everything to go through
twenty items
we're going to get back to our mean
you're being zero
we can use that to test the nazi era
where to go ahead and print out that
line
so we should see a lot less stuff coming
back to our screen
so say that
give another run
and if you look here at the index number
on the left
three or four eighty
five hundred five-twenty before that was
going
and pretty every single line our
printing every twenty f wine
sometimes operators like mine
i don't have to have that they need to
use it for anything it's a very
infrequent that i need to know the
remainder of something within fourteen
point
but it has a great properly keys here
for a very simple monitoring
stepping through stuff
sophie scroll back at the top
you can see that we it doesn't take very
many lines to cover when doing every
twenty
so here we can see
one of our files the hatter and then we
step into the data
so you're not seeing every single line
that would have come out
and it tends to be very do this
now we've been asking for both try a way
that give us more flexibility where the
user can specify which files to work on
python
there is a sis module so important
s y s
and the system marginal
if you see psystar r_d_
i'm sorry about the name but it comes
from the nineteen seventies
c and
and it what it means is if the arguments
for the command line
so if we hit enter
in a series of type prince
psystar carvey
what about the same
it gives you back a list of all the
kremlin arguments for that particular
call
so in this case if you wait for my pipe
on that was how i pipe bomb was called
and we didn't get any argument so it's
just showing us that it brand user
bandai python
so the first one is always
the uh... system rb sub-zero is can
always be program it was called and
anything that comes after that
is then going to be
the command-line arguments
in this case we see a print psystar r_v_
square brackets
one colon
this isn't gonna print anything for us
because there's nothing there
if we call the program
with a bunch of options they were still
using dash my lab without a fight on
that would show up here
and with that
we can actually
let the user specified
which file through what you so worried
in the notes
here's how we use that line rather than
the cloth
do you create
an aspect up our program of the cash to
specify which aspects we want to use it
on
with this controllers two
control exp jump
packed aspect
in your main function
four file name involved dot gov
we're gonna get rid of co-op board gom
and replaced that with psystar r_v_
one colon
in square brackets
and we need to import sets
that the important thing mobile finds
that we are needed to see the top
i can remember him or her anything too
important gang now the big deal
and now we can specify
what files we'd like to have and are
and make a little bit
here see what's going on right below the
starting main let me say prints
psystar carvey
colin
com ar sys dot r_v_ so you can see what
arguments are being passed in
this is the typical debugging where
print rather than using uh...
traditional wagner
which takes a while i'm
so let's try running that to run
aspect to our client
and right now assist pass in the sample
but aspect for the city one
presenter
you'll see that i'm a typo
by changing things up
i need to move my imports
t_v_ for the print
since i use is right here
and i had sis imported after
i tried to use it
appear on that
we've only did
the expect our party concedes this tardy
consisted of our aspect up by program
position zero
and then sample but aspect in position
one
what you guys if you got that working
rerun recommending admit
another aspect bio on there
u_n_ allies you'll see you have a couple
aspects in the directory
we have won his first with two thousand
and ten
so we've ran out before run aspect up
like simple but aspect
acute two thousand ten
press tab
who know how to u_s_ that files
press enter
and it will run both of them
and if we see here our system hardy
now has three things in it
differ from the air program a moment to
file stuffed into it
so this way
you can let the person who is using your
aspect top tyco tech which files they
want around me who had ten thousand
aspects of directory
that they worked on projects with tens
of thousands of files
probly don't wanna run unprocessed all
of them at one time you may be just
working on some
ficar aspect of it
it it doesn't know silicate to try and
process them all at once
so that was
b part vi wave directly handling it and
you can write really fancy parsers
yourself for command lines
please don't do that
hwy people
feel that they can make their own better
than everyone else
then you end up with eighty million ways
to parse the command line and you meet
people like me go completely insane
so we're going to use the fight on way
that create command-line arguments that
the official
blacks way of creating fancy command
line so you can say dash dash help
habitat helped
as you add arguments
you create your doing it in a way that
other people understand because
everybody's using the same approach
to sell put up before go on
we have a whole lot of zeros in there
when the company aspect for atlanta has
no data it likes to write
zero zero zero for the position
as that jack garbage dump of
position data that's right off of africa
there
where it lost data goes to die
there's there's there was a really bad
choice for an update of value
if you try and part of his that's who
often see all kinds of things plodding
repair of africa dismissing it might be
there
so let's try it
the arguing parser
becomes with python
it's called hard parts there's an old
one called opt parse
that's the one that's in all of my coat
dot music it sold
and so will start off by saying import
our parks
will try it out
inside of i'd fight on first
and here i recommend just copying and
pasting for now to go quick
so here i said archer equals hard parts
argument parser
eyes kinda wordy
any to pass a description
so we now have a parser
and we can save
hearts
equals
parser
parse args
and it would give the parsing
in this case nothing's gonna happen
because we had
we had no arguments to pass in was a
very exciting
what it will do is give us some options
to go ahead and creates
whatever arguments
who's going to go ahead dvd example and
in order to get to knows better
you want to read the documentation alter
and create some videos with two more
examples
but will do here's this line is going to
say anything that doesn't happen
i dash dash or dash
thing too is going to become a part of
our file names list
it's mimetype string
and every time you see anyone add to the
less that's what this is an art things
means
and will do that this will call
args
harsh dot parse args it's going to go
work since he'd given the option to look
at that sister party
and figure out what the heck soon there
and handle it for us
so let's go ahead and copy this into our
code
sold to you uh...
minute wm
trolex too
move control exp
and so we before we had sisson
all this other junk will comment that
out
so i'm copying
backroom of lines from the notes
so important
our partners
and bring to build a parser that looks
at our command line
a memory say four file name in arch dot
filings
so we're told that here
this is going to be a name
file name since can magically courageous
littlest in their anything that we have
a collective
to go ahead and safer
you know if we save run aspect up pint
dash dash help
who have better work
press an error
this looks more like a traditional one x
organi style
command-line arguments
it gives you a built-in help
that as you add arguments
fell appear down to bottom here
your descriptions in there
the nice thing about this tool visits
written to handle all those we are cases
where people do things that you would
never expect
though do you
but the list of filings first animal
have all the dash dash argument
afterwards
stuff like that that's really hard to
write a person for people taken time to
to do it right here is that not to worry
about
handling things
so now if we save ron aspect up i was
nothing
are following simplicity and think
it got upset with us for some reason
picture
with them
yet so there's a lot of magic happening
behind the scenes
so what is going to you is that we build
up all these arguments and so you can
add things like we're added dash dash
ask you like
to right now the database
if we have an argument when he said
access help is going to look at all
those and radio human readable or at
least more readable
form out the arguments
in a way that you might get a few brenda
from the command line
who's trying to basically bill up dot
infrastructure and
i've seen people write this code and it
takes in about a hundred lines to get to
where you are like that so it's nice to
have a library where
well i know this is hard to follow in
here
if you've read through the docking
station look at a few more examples of
starting the pattern and then you can
start adding more arguments
and options cheer code and you can build
up something looks pretty powerful
there's our air way back up here
for being or a knife i bought it also
decided is that nice
trace back it was really confusing
now we said that we have to have one or
more file names
when i gave it no falling into the said
too few arguments
and then a portrait throughout powell
trip back to us
so it's now rerun it with our sample but
aspect
now it handles that
decades so we uh...
out of print statement in
free here to print
file names
heartstart file names
warrior on that
sir right after the yards equal parser
dot parse args
what approach to the following two cc m
and if we re run that
and missy appear file name is
so that i want to add a second file
sonam able at the two thousand eleven
file
press answer to run both of them
legacy file names
is a list of
art usda files
so this is how i would add controlling
or weight control
pursing a whole bunch of different files
together
and deciding which ones are picked from
a directory
if you want to run all of them
unfortunately in here at the star won't
work
but if we do it controls the
and we're going back to the bash shell
i haven't really job control before
clean
i wish i'd show you guys this before but
you can suspend programs
and so i used it controls each
to suspend
that suspend your program
and the terminal
and we're gonna give you exceed
for for granted
effecting running against what effect i
packed up section
we can spend forever going to all these
really call unfair useful but
which i have a limited amount of time
so see till two slash class
slash twenty four
if you do in our special
you can see we have
simple
aspect and has picked up high
now it's not executed or we don't have
that x fight over their so we can say
see each month
plus x pets pet tough time
yeah could you tell us that sells for
about hai
will see that we have an executed war
aspect
and still collard greens
never can run that sold as pet stopped
by dash dash help
we get that same help that we have a
four so here's our
will help section
have been saved on slash aspect up i
sample
uh... aspect
thought great now who want to handle the
mall
if we're not in our fight on that's the
key factor because here
we can say da slash aspect opt by
star dot aspect
this is going to process
every single aspect that directory
that starr does it work inside of my
part of the partially
so that ben zips through all of those
files
and so here the prominence was all three
of them
will do the f_d_a_ commands to get back
and i fight on
press and terror
it shows you wish programmer in it
where you are so ignore that president
urge us just to get back to europe right
on prompt
and make sure that you were in class
twenty four
i think that's an example suffering that
now let's go ahead and take this code
and let's go look at these
files because
it really sucks not to see where they
are on the globe
so i'd like to see the three
aspect files on the globe
through used
relief areas that were valuable for over
a changed up a little bit
so for the guitar aspect upline
so in here
right now we're just looking through and
printing out each time
who would like to do is bright out
eight came off island
so let's go up and add the functionality
to be able to write out a camel finally
here
so each time through the loop
right after our friend file name will
say out equals open
if i say finally end
we're gonna step
that would step right on top of that
file the return of reading kill it
which we don't want to you
so i have extension to until say farming
plus
dot came out
in this training
says the hope of a file
nap we did this in tried to write to
what will be wrong
i would not work
at one of the violent but while that's
not what is right ah...
as output file wanna write to you
if we've opened this cleary from it
andy field at this point
we can do it read from this one but we
actually threw out a right to this
we actually have to tell them on a right
to it
soon-yi uh... w it
string at the end there
to open for writing
farid in writing
and this case it doesn't
help you at all because we're not gonna
go back and read and write
we want to just brain only
if you're going to be a pending to
something going back and reading from it
but generally that's if you get that
kind of case
i attended try not to program work
having a file and filling with that i
try to create a new files completely
uh... that the other hand
outside
i don't think i've done reading right
and watch ten years
so i'm kinda
shy away from that
so that was opened it let's go ahead to
write out the came out better
section before we had some template
files so we can just do it for inside of
here
so i recommend just copying this right
now because team owners
are very fine
for peace that
breeding here so we've got four
parliament artists
print file name
we've been done this
output
and here looks like i've got an indent
problems on an oppressed tab
we condemned the raid number of spaces
nima rating out
scattered section
and this is
back two x somehow or we have actually
gone into detail
indicando format
this says were
creating an x in our file
it's gonna be a camel
and then insider that will create
document placemark
renews the format
there's the format but for my down here
who are put in a file name
as our title
and the ritualized according to the
right out another
wine that shows where the chip plant
patients ask file
now we also need to close up the end of
that
that will create the hatter
inside this loop weeks for each datagram
wind
pick out the x_ in the wind break them
into our camo
so can do in there
bring it out here
notes that we are now insight about
their statement we don't want to be
inside of that because i think it will
only write every ten point
error files aren't that big
if you get into the real aspect that has
been down down sampled
you wanna do probably every
i think in every
ten thousand points because that's pets
are
the really big
source a house dot right
andrewmar pasig acts
in crude races come on
wine cruelly braces
and then slash and is a new line
and that string policy doc format
and so now we can say
need to pass in the acts in the line
will be doing it this way we're going to
pick out the exim line out of the
datagram
so will say acts equals
long degrees
and wayy equals the aquarium
degrees
this is where it goes to a sort of
electric
or with the press see matching helps
because i can see that
i have one for a parent to see rehearing
smashing
uniform at
but i also have one over here that i
have attached seperately one more
style matching
the right and what's going to have those
will say that
and again i'm in a copy
b
fail part of this
that has to get ready at the end of the
came out
cemented w
infect pigs that
right after the four loop member before
leave
inventing is right here so i need to
step out because i'm a liberating one
ko part the finishes up the file
we're going to look through and for each
one of those
we're gonna add-in
the point
both say that
hopefully we've don't have any typos
grammar on this and see how it looks
before we send off to a trade war
pc running
aspect
applied simple
uh... aspect when its hand tab
and twenty eleven tab
press answer
and now into an analyst at shell and
looking at directory
cross your fingers and hopefully there
should be
three came off while
figures one
here's another one
and there's our sample blood
aspect that came out
and let's take a look at that twenty
eleven file
so what's
twenty eleven
pressed haven't and then put a period
came out on the end
and see how it works
it's still too early ok im hae speech to
go down
greats
except for the zeros
so we have busy lives and their
so we need to be able to extracted the
zeros out of the file because
if we draw a line on the air and some of
the points go thru zero but inferential
from when we are
over africa and back
very helpful
since we're running out of time i'm
going to show you in the notes briefly
what will be doing
and will try and do it on next thursday
because next tuesday's committee rob
last well with
are doing statistics
hours are free tool for
doing some really amazing cisco analysis
it can link up with python
sore lucky enough to have rob be willing
to come and join us
we need to be able to compare against
zero for a floating point number so the
one thing the type of his income what it
seems kind of obvious is
floating-point comparisons can't be
directly equal
you have to have some sort of routing
error willingness and your code
ever to function cult almost equal
and defaults to using this up four and
put it to the return i want to use for
that rounding error that you're willing
to tolerate
and icon does have built into the uh...
sis dot
float underscore info dot capsule and a
default on its pretty small
work done as they can function and take
the default one that the pipeline gives
you is that's not good enough you can
set your own and take a quick peak acts
that value so with you
imports
sis
psystar
floats press pound
amnesty for underscore info
period than tab again
there's a whole lot of junk
but if we tried
epsilon press and tears
you'll see there are so honest you point
two times and the mind of sixteen
so it's a small small round here in this
case
zero point zero isn't always equal to
zero point zero
and don't want to get caught by that
so this function will handle that check
and will go out and abend became ill
come for next time to throw out those
bad points
certainly part of the aspect not to see
it on the globe
and i will jump into creating a database
our guys have a great thanksgiving
don't show up to class on thursday